National Association of Schools of Art (U.S.) Records
National Association of Schools of Art (U.S.) Records
1944-1979
National Association of Schools of Art (U.S.)
11.0 linear ft.
Organizational records, including correspondence (1960-1975); membership lists (1946-1956); minutes (1949-1974), reports; and treasurers' records (1948-1956).
149351
Biographical History
The National Association of Schools of Art (NASA) was founded in 1944 as the National Association of Schools of Design (NASD). In 1966, it became the National Association of Schools of Art, and in 1981 it became the National Association of Schools of Art and Design (NASAD).
NASAD member schools of art and design are primarily at the college level, but include postsecondary non-degree-granting schools for the visual arts. NASAD is the national accrediting agency for art and design and art and design-related disciplines. The Association also provides information to the public, produces statistical research, provides professional development for leaders of art and design schools, and engages in policy analysis.
[Adapted from NASAD website, http://nasad.arts-accredit.org.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The National Association of Schools of Art (U.S.) Records consists of general files, treasurer's records, and miscellaneous. The collection includes some unprocessed additions not reflected in this inventory.
Arrangement of the Collection
Files are arranged roughly alphabetically.
Related Material
has many collections relating to art and artists of all types -- sculptors, illustrators, painters, designers, cartoonists, and more. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
National Association of Schools of Art (U.S.) -- Archives.; National Association of Schools of Art and Design (U.S.) -- Archives.; Art -- Study and teaching.; Art schools -- Societies, etc.; Annual reports.; Correspondence.; Membership lists.; Minutes (administrative records); Reports.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- General files
  - Accreditation
    - Comments on (Box 1)
    - Meetings, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Accreditation Committee
    - Questionnaire (Box 1)
    - Interim report (Box 1)
    - Talks on (Box 1)
    - National Committee correspondence (Box 1)
  - Admissions
    - Reapplication for NASD (National Association of Schools of Design), 1951 (Box 1)
    - Questionnaire (Box 1)
  - Admissions and Accreditation Procedures Handbook (Box 1)
  - Affidavits (Box 1)
  - Akron Art Institute (Box 1)
  - Alabama Polytechnic Institute (Box 1)
  - Alabama University (Box 1)
  - Albright Art School (Box 1)
  - Alcott, John E. (Box 1)
  - Alfred University (Box 1)
  - Analysis Guide (Box 1)
  - Archives (Box 1)
  - Art Academy of Cincinnati (Box 1)
  - Art Center School (Box 1)
  - Art Department (Box 1)
  - Art School of The Art Institute of Chicago, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Art School Society of Arts and Crafts (Box 1)
  - Atlanta Art Institute (Box 1)
  - Auburn University (Alabama) (Box 1)
  - Bach, Richard F. (Box 1)
  - Bulletin (Box 1)
  - California College of Arts and Crafts, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - California Institute of the Arts (Box 2)
  - California School of Fine Arts (Box 2)
  - Careers In Art (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology (Box 2)
  - J.C. Chambers (Box 2)
  - Chicago, The School of the Art Institute of (Box 2)
  - Chouinard Art Institute (Box 2)
  - Cincinnati, Art Academy of (Box 2)
  - Cincinnati, University of (Box 2)
  - Citations (Box 2)
  - Cleveland Institute of Art, The (Box 2)
  - Committees
    - Fellow and Citation (Box 2)
    - Standards Information (Box 2)
  - Competition procedures, 1949; 1955,; 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Completed copy (Box 2)
  - Conference
    - Second NASD (National Association of Schools of Design), 1944-1946 (Box 2)
    - Annual, Oct. 16-18, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1948-1949; 1952-1955,; 1960-1963,; 1970,; 1976 (Box 2)
  - Constitution, NASD (National Association of Schools of Design)
    - Old amendments (Box 2)
    - Constitution (Box 2)
  - Cooper Union Art School (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Pre-1960 (Box 2)
    - 1960-1963, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - 1964-1968, 1971, 1973-1975, 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, NASD (National Association of Schools of Design), 1949; 1951-1960; 14 folders (Box 3)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art (Box 3)
  - Dayton Art Institute (Box 3)
  - M. Descours (Box 4)
  - Directory (Box 4)
  - Division III (Box 4)
  - Faculty suggestions (Box 4)
  - Farnum, Royal B. (Box 4)
  - Forms (Box 4)
  - General information regarding NASD (Box 4)
  - Hartford University (Box 4)
  - John Herron Art School, The (Box 4)
  - Herron Art School (Box 4)
  - Higher education (Box 4)
  - Hudson, Kenneth E. (Box 4)
  - Illinois, University of (Box 4)
  - Kansas City Art Institute (Box 4)
  - Kansas City Art Institute and School of Design (Box 4)
  - Kansas, University of (Box 4)
  - J. Lander (Box 4)
  - Layton School of Art (Box 4)
  - Letters to NASD members (Box 4)
  - List of Material sent out according to date (Box 4)
  - Maryland Institute (Box 4)
  - Massachusetts School of Art (Box 4)
  - Membership Lists, NASD, 1946-1947; 1951-1956; 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Membership Lists and Rosters, NASD (Box 4)
  - NASA (National Association of Schools of Art)
    - Preparations for meetings, 1965; 1966 (Box 4)
    - Annual meeting, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Minutes of annual meetings
      - Third, Nov. 28, 1949 (Box 4)
      - Fourth, Nov. 27-28, 1950 (Box 4)
      - Fifth, Nov. 25-28, 1951 (Box 4)
      - Seventh, Oct. 16-19, 1953 (Box 4)
      - Eighth, 1954 (Box 5)
      - Ninth, Oct. 15-17 1955 (Box 5)
      - Eleventh, Oct. 1957 (Box 5)
      - Twelfth, Oct. 1958 (Box 5)
      - Fourteenth, Oct. 1960 (Box 5)
      - Fifteenth, Oct. 1961 (Box 5)
      - Sixteenth, Oct. 1962 (Box 5)
      - Seventeenth, Oct. 1963 (Box 5)
      - Eighteenth, Oct. 1964 (Box 5)
      - 1971 (Box 5)
      - 1972 (Box 5)
      - 1974 (Box 5)
  - Annual meeting, program for 1956 (Box 5)
  - Supplement to NASD Minutes of Jan. 1953 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1948-1951; 1953,; 1955-1961; 11 folders (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors regular meeting minutes, 1970-1974; 1977; 7 folders (Box 5)
  - NASD National Conference at C.I.A., 1947 (Box 5)
  - Conference on Accreditation, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Executive Board meeting, 1949; 1954; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Meeting of Executive Committee, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, Jan. 6, 1951; May 19, 1951; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - NASD meetings, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Memphis Academy of the Arts (Box 5)
  - Michigan, University of (Box 5)
  - Middle States Association (Box 5)
  - Minneapolis School of Art (Box 5)
  - NASA minutes and reports
    - 1960-1962, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - NASA minutes of Board meeting, 1967-1969; 9 folders (Box 6)
  - Moore Institute of Art, Science, and Industry (Box 6)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, The School (Box 6)
  - NASA, 1947-1949; 1961-1966,; 1972-1974; 10 folders (Box 6)
  - NASA Discussion Section reports, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
  - NASA rewrite (Box 6)
  - National Conference of Schools of Design, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - NASA supplies on file (Box 6)
  - National Council on Art (Box 6)
  - NASD miscellaneous, 1964 (Box 6)
  - NASD permanent mailing roster (Box 6)
  - NASD releases, 1949-1955 (Box 6)
  - NCATE (National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education) Meeting, Chicago (Box 7)
  - New York University (Box 7)
  - Officers of NASD list (Box 7)
  - Panel discussions, 1949; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Parson's School of Design (Box 7)
  - Past inquiries, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Pickering, Ernest (Box 7)
  - Philadelphia Museum School (Box 7)
  - Portland Museum Art School (Box 7)
  - Postcards (Box 7)
  - Pratt Institute (Box 8)
  - President's Page (The) (Box 8)
  - Press releases, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Professional Art Education Association (Box 8)
  - Professional School Analysis Guide, Apr. 15, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Publications (Box 8)
  - Publications pending (Box 8)
  - Questionnaires, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - NASD questionnaires, 1949; 1955; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Regionals (Box 8)
  - Report of progress to members, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Report on Washington Conference, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Requests for rosters, 1957; 1958-1959; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Requests for NASA directory (Box 8)
  - Rhode Island School of Design (Box 8)
  - Rice, Harold R. (Box 8)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology (Box 8)
  - Roll call (Box 8)
  - Roster, 1957-1962; 1964; 7 folders (Box 8)
  - San Francisco Art Institute (Box 8)
  - Silvermine College of Art (Box 8)
  - Special NASA appointments (Box 8)
  - Statement of Purpose, NASD (Box 8)
  - Surveys (Box 8)
  - Syracuse University (Box 8)
  - United States Government Publications (Box 8)
  - Upholstery And Leather Group (Box 8)
  - Fredrick Wallace (Box 8)
  - Washington School of Art (Box 8)
  - Washington University (Box 8)
  - Worchester Art Museum (Box 8)
- Treasurer's records
  - Miscellaneous, 1948-1956; 8 folders (Box 8)
  - Membership dues
    - 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - 1971-1972
      - Division I (Box 8)
      - Division II (Box 8)
      - Division III (Box 8)
    - 1972-1973
      - Division I (Box 9)
      - Division II (Box 9)
      - Division III (Box 9)
  - Cash receipts, 1969-1973; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Bills paid, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Membership, 1973-1974
    - Div. I (Box 9)
    - Div. II (Box 9)
    - Div. III (Box 9)
    - Div. V (Box 9)
  - Cash disbursements, 1970-1973; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Annual meeting notes and back-up material, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Cash receipts, Fiscal Year 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Fiscal Year pending (Box 9)
  - General non-current (Box 9)
  - Telephone credit card numbers (Box 9)
  - Annual Meeting (Texas), 1971 (Box 9)
  - Annual Meeting (Atlanta), Oct. 22-24, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Spring Board Meeting, Milwaukee, 1970 (Box 9)
  - R.C. Rathbone and Co. (Box 9)
  - Journal (Box 9)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1949-1950; 1955-1956; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Duties of Secretary and National Office (Box 9)
  - East Carolina College Account (Box 9)
  - Bank statements, 1970-1974; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Check stub records, Jan 1968-Jan 1973; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Magnetic cards (Box 10)
  - Microfilms, 6 reels (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Micsellaneous oversize (Oversize 1)